Ò×¿¼·¶ÎÄ°Ë
In the cartoon,
a girl tells her mother on the phone that she cannot go back home
and spend the National Day holiday together with her parents
because she has booked a sightseeing trip.
The girl looks happy but her aged mother disappointed.
It goes without saying that this cartoon mirrors the relationship
between adult children and their elderly parents.
Nowadays, the increasingly fierce competition compels people to
make every effort to work. And they make use of their precious spare time
to entertain themselves as an escape from stressful reality.
Therefore, they practically have no time to spend together with their parents.
The aged parents, on the other hand,
overwhelmed by a vacuum when they retire from their jobs,
have nothing to do but long for their children to come back.
As far as I can see,
the quality of the relationship between parents and children
is of supreme significance.
It is also important that parents feel happy in the knowledge that they are loved.
That is to say, children need to spend more time with their parents
and express love and concern about them.
In addition, it is advisable for the parents to accept the fact that
sooner or later their children will leave them for an independent life.
By looking for social circles of their own and cultivating hobbies
such as writing, painting and singing, elderly parents
will enjoy a more meaningful life in their remaining years.